<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wikidot="http://www.wikidot.com/rss-namespace">

	<channel>
		<title>Comments for page &quot;A Protocol for Dying&quot;</title>
		<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show</link>
		<description></description>
				<copyright></copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 11:25:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2713853</guid>
				<title>End of year letter to Pieter: 3 post-puzzles</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2713853</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 04:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Nell Henderson</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>844555</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Dear Pieter</p> <p>Now you are no longer here, I need some advice on what to do and how to think about things, now you are no longer here! From you I am learning to be brief, and in that spirit, have three puzzles for you!</p> <p>1. How can I - like you - turn weaknesses into strengths? You were gregarious to overcome shyness; played music to express your hidden feelings. You had a really smart way to live! How can I learn to do this too?</p> <p>2. How can I be there for your kids? You warned me this might not be easy. Yet they are like sunshine to us on a rainy day. Please give me a clue Pieter: how can I be a good auntie?</p> <p>3. How can we find peace? You and Frans, our father, both died this year. Those of us who remain need to live in harmony. But is this possible? How can we find peace?</p> <p>Thanks bro! With love for 2017 when it comes.</p> <p>Yours - Nellie</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2713788</guid>
				<title>Re: Dag Pieter</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2713788</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 02:06:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Nell Henderson</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>844555</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Dag Geert! Ik zou jou graag weer zien - kan jij misschien address sturen naar <span class="wiki-email">moc.liamg|snejtnih#moc.liamg|snejtnih</span> - wil jou ook en boek photos van Pieter en Frans sturen. Kusjes - Leen xxx</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2667944</guid>
				<title>Thank you</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2667944</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 06:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>NuLL3rr0r</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2853216</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>R.I.P. Pieter Hintjens!</p> <p>Thank you so much for the great projects, books and your protocol for dying that you left behind. It's a very solid and thoughtful read. Recently, I've experienced loss of a friend and also my grandfather which despite the negative psychological impact as a whole affected me in a better way. I must go through it again cause I think it will help me put it all together.</p> <p>Your kids must be grateful and proud to have such a father.</p> <p>Thank you!</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2666781</guid>
				<title>A Protocol for Living</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2666781</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 14:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>jedmedgrey</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2833871</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>To Pieter's children: you had an extraordinary Father. Because of that, you still have, and will continue to have, his strong positive influence in your lives. His words will be available when you need them, and his wisdom and humor will help you through the trials you will face as you grow up, become adults, and as you face your own, inevitable, deaths.</p> <p>Pieter's words apply to Life - to living it well, openly, honestly, and without denying a basic fact: we will all die. We may not know how or when, but every one of us will die.</p> <p>We can accept that fact and live our lives well, being kind and generous to those around us, contributing in our chosen professions, and helping the world be a better place in ways both small and large. The gifts we receive, as Pieter learned, are immeasurable, full of love, joy, friends and family.</p> <p>Or we can be mean, petty, selfish, jealous, greedy, grabbing only for ourselves. We might wind up with more monetary wealth and material goods than we ever thought possible. It doesn't matter in the end: we still die, and we cannot take money or goods with us when we do.</p> <p>How much better to be surrounded by loved ones, both family and friends, during our last months, weeks, days, hours. What a gift to be able to decide exactly when that last moment will be, so we can ensure that we have the love, support, and comfort to face the end calmly and yes, joyously, but also to give those we care about the chance to help us through those last minutes. We don't have to die alone, and our loved ones don't have to regret that they were not there, that they &quot;let&quot; us go alone, perhaps afraid and sad, without someone there saying &quot;We love you, and it is okay for you to leave us now.&quot;</p> <p>Please check on the laws where you live and add your voice to those that support &quot;Right to Die&quot; and &quot;Death with Dignity&quot; legislation. Volunteer for Hospice, visit people in long-term care facilities and hospitals who do not have family and friends to do so. Your lives will be richer for it, and who knows, you may reap the benefits when it is your time to pass from this beautiful blue and green world.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2555543</guid>
				<title>I loved Social Architecture</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2555543</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 04:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>omidfi</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2809261</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I loved social architecture, and now I'm reading the psychpath code.</p> <p>Have you read Marcel Proust? Your writing reads on itself so smoothly, to me it seems like I'm reading Proust.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2528458</guid>
				<title>Thank you</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2528458</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 21:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>santhoshknn</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2777076</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Dear Pieter,</p> <p>I wanted to drop a note sincerely thank you for the book The Psychopath code. Having had the misfortune of working with people who are pure evil, your book was really helpful. I hope to read it again (just bought the Kindle edition). Thank you again for your writing. Your children are truly lucky to have a father like you and I am sure they will be happy to read all the comments from strangers whose lives you have touched.</p> <p>Thank you again.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2515035</guid>
				<title>Things I relate to</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2515035</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 00:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Dieter Gillis</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2754325</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Hi Pieter</p> <p>I just saw your 'Trick-better-software'.<br /> Mainly to hear your voice. I don't understand 90% of what you're saying. But I connect when you talk about Minecraft. My boys (5 and 6y.) play it at a basic level. And I love that it is that basic for learning programming. I hope it gives my boys a basis for working with computers and programming later on.<br /> I got even more thrilled when you explain why working together is important and especially with young kids. You adress a topic I don't hear a lot. Please, learn from kids. Copy their open view on the world and respect and prize their contribution.<br /> Thank you.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2514735</guid>
				<title>Bedankt!</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2514735</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 10:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Sofie76</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2753721</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Beste Pieter</p> <p>Ik was 17&#160;en een ramp op de weg en bovendien zag ik het nut van te leren rijden helemaal niet in. Iedereen die mij wou leren rijden, werd na een tijdje zenuwachtig omdat ik er echt niets van bakte. Zelfs de lessen in de rijschool hadden tot niet veel resultaat geleid.</p> <p>Toen bood jij aan om mij te leren rijden. Je rustige persoonlijkheid, je vragen (wie rijdt er nu achter jou? Welke kleur heeft de auto achter jou?), je motiverende woorden, enz. zorgden ervoor dat ik in amper 2 uur zelfzekerheid en zin om te rijden kreeg!</p> <p>Ik krijg vaak complimenten over mijn rijstijl en over mijn parkeertechniek en elke keer vertel ik aan de complimentengever dat het dankzij jou is dat ik dat alles kan, dat het dankzij jou is dat ik kan rijden :)</p> <p>Heel erg bedankt daarvoor! Jij was het misschien al vergeten, maar ik denk nog bijna dagelijks &quot;en wie rijdt er nu achter mij en welke kleur heeft de auto?&quot; :)</p> <p>Heel veel liefs!<br /> Sofie</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2513053</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2513053</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 01:39:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>uhlmann</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>14554</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Hi Pieter,</p> <p>I like your protocol, such a great piece of humanism.<br /> We met in FFII some years ago. It was quite a ride. :)<br /> Just want to wish you and your family all the best.</p> <p>Stephan</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2509821</guid>
				<title>Re: ...read what other people say about their dad</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2509821</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 13:08:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>ultrabug</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2744971</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Ahah oui, j'ai pensé Belge et écris Hollandais à cause de cette langue bizarre ! désolé :)</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2509723</guid>
				<title>Re: ...read what other people say about their dad</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2509723</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 09:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Belge, on es des belges pas des Hollandais&#8230; :) C'est vrai qu'on parl Neerlandais aussi a la maison.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2509690</guid>
				<title>...read what other people say about their dad</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2509690</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 07:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>ultrabug</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2744971</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Ok Pieter, being a dad since a few months it took me some time to actually start writing this down as I relate strongly with you and your loved ones.</p> <p>Since I've had the chance to meet you and your kids at EuroPython 2014 in Berlin, I'll address to them in their mother's tongue.</p> <p>&#8212;</p> <p>Cela fait bientôt deux ans que j'ai rencontré votre père, dans l'une de ces nombreuses conférences auxquelles il participe et où il vous avait amené.</p> <p>Je garde de lui l'image d'une personne inspirée et source d'inspiration qui a parlé à des centaines de personnes pendant une heure sans une forme apparante de préparation. C'était la première fois que je voyais cela et ses idées et points de vue m'ont beaucoup intéressé.</p> <p>J'utilisais à l'époque une des technologies dont votre père est à l'origine et je rencontrais quelques difficultés avec son utilisation dans des cas assez particuliers. J'ai alors participé à la formation qu'il donnait durant la conférence afin d'avoir l'occasion de lui parler pour qu'il m'aide et me convainc de continuer à utiliser cette technologie que j'aime tant.</p> <p>Cela ne va sûrement pas vous surprendre, mais rien ne s'est passé comme je l'avais prévu :)</p> <p>J'ai en réalité participé à une formation moins technique que philosophique et méthodologique sur le &quot;comment travailler efficacement ensemble dans le monde de l'Open Source&quot;. J'y ai vu de jeunes enfants (vous!) y déambuler et se faire embrasser par leur père qui (à ma grande surprise) leur parlait Français.</p> <p>M'a-t-il convaincu de continuer à utiliser la technologie en question ? Non, il m'a lui-même convaincu du contraire !</p> <p>Ce que je retiens de votre père ? Un grand Hollandais, sourire aux lèvres, super accessible et doux avec ses enfants m'ayant donné une forte impression de liberté et de bonheur. Je n'oublierai pas la lueur dans ses yeux quand ils se posaient sur vous : vivez libres et heureux !</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2509613</guid>
				<title>Re: Thanks for ZeroMQ and &#039;The Psycopath Code&#039;</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2509613</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 03:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Wow, thank you for the story. It's rare that people tell us what they do with ZeroMQ. You did a good job&#8230; it's not the code you write that matters as much as all the complexity you <em>don't</em> introduce that does.</p> <p>And I'm so glad you like the books.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2509453</guid>
				<title>Thanks for ZeroMQ and &#039;The Psycopath Code&#039;</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2509453</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 20:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>evadeflow</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2744436</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Hi, Pieter. We've not met, but I'm a big fan of your work. I'd like to share an anecdote about how ZeroMQ helped me get past a rough patch in my career.</p> <p>In the summer of 2013, a friend of mine—who I'd done some freelance work for in the past—asked me if I had time to help him get a new business venture going. He was pursuing a contract with another company to deliver realtime location data for professional athletes during games. The idea was to sew RFID tags into the jerseys of every player, and use an array of sensors arranged around the periphery of each stadium to receive the data. My friend had just received sample hardware from <em>his</em> customer, and needed somebody to write a proof-of-concept C++ application that would collect data from the hardware and disseminate it to various downstream processing nodes.</p> <p>I was pretty busy with my 'real' job at the time, but it was an interesting enough project that I told him I'd find time for it. Somehow. The comm to the hardware was via a standard TCP socket, so we thought it should be pretty easy to just read data from this socket, convert it to a more efficient/user-friendly encoding (think: msgpack, Protobuf, Thrift, etc) and ship it downstream using a <tt>ZMQ_PUB</tt> socket. And it was. In the end, I delivered a few hundred lines of code structured as two nested loops inside a single <tt>main()</tt> function. I wrote this code in a single weekend, and billed my friend for a total of 20 hours. It maybe wasn't the best code I've written, but my friend only needed some 'seed' code to use in early demos, and said he would hire somebody to punch it into shape later.</p> <p>Fast-forwarding 18 months: my employer laid off my entire development team! I'd never been laid off before, but before I could work myself into a panic about what to do next, my friend got word about my situation and contacted me. The sports project had been a <em>huge</em> success. My friend offered me a job immediately!</p> <p>So, I'm grateful that the tiny bit of ZMQ work I did in 2013 helped me weather what could have been a difficult situation almost two years later. But the biggest surprise was seeing the nature of the changes my new team had been forced to make to my code in the interim. I expected the code to look quite different, but, to my shock/delight, the only changes were the addition of a few command line arguments for diagnostics/debugging, and some code to read settings from a config file. For the most part, the code I wrote in a single weekend was the same code my new employer had used to ship some 10 <em>billion</em> location data packets during 130 sporting events in 2014!</p> <p>Had I not used ZeroMQ for this, I don't believe such a feat would have been possible. The semantics of <tt>ZMQ_PUB</tt> were just such a <em>perfect</em> fit that I only needed a tiny bit of glue code to tie everything together. I've since teased apart the single <tt>main()</tt> function so I could get tests around the message-parsing/conversion bits, but ZMQ is still doing most of the heavy lifting for us. And it Just Works™. So&#8230; thanks to you and the community you've built for that.</p> <p>Thanks, too, for writing 'The Psycopath Code'. I happened across it on Amazon about 6 weeks ago and was intrigued when I recognized your name. I couldn't put my Kindle down until I'd completed it—really fascinating stuff. My brain is <em>still</em> processing it. One of the main things I took from it is just how taxing it is for me, personally, to get angry. Guilt, Shame and Remorse always come hard on the heels of Anger, so I really don't like to go there. I've noticed before that not everybody seems to pay this same cost, and dealing with those people is <em>exhausting</em>. Your book, more than anything, has helped me become aware of my own 'emotional chains', so I don't have to expend as much of my own energy to process encounters with people that are able to wield anger as a weapon with (seemingly) zero personal cost. I've always just referred to those people as 'assholes', but you've made me realize that the damage they do is: 1) <em>very</em> real, and 2) much more pernicious than I'd imagined. I don't have any psycopaths trying to feed on me at the moment, but I'll be ready for the next one that tries to chew on me.</p> <p>The 'ZMQ Guide' and 'The Pyscopath Code' were such great reads that I picked up 'Culture &amp; Empire' yesterday. I haven't read much of it yet, but it, too, seems fascinating. I'm going to get back to reading it now, in fact. Just wanted to leave you this note saying how helpful your work has been to me&#8230;</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2508775</guid>
				<title>Dag Pieter</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2508775</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 12:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Geert Hintjens</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2743132</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Dag Pieter,</p> <p>Katelijne zond het bericht uit De Standaard door, waarmee ik in één klap geïnformeerd werd over jouw verdere leven en nakende dood. Plots schiet de knop op de tijdlijn heen en weer. Wat gisteren toekomst was, is vandaag voorbije tijd. Wat lang geleden was, is nu een levendig beeld.</p> <p>Jij leerde ons Swahili. Een mini-woordenboekje in kinderhandschrift lag jaren later nog in ons huis. Wij leerden jou verkeersregels op de fiets. Na enkele angstige momenten in de straten van Schoten.</p> <p>Van jouw vader is er het beeld hoe hij, eindelijk even terug in België, plots bij de keukendeur stond, en mijn moeder in droefheid omhelsde. Mijn kindergedachten van toen: Zoveel tranen nog? Mijn vader is toch lang dood?</p> <p>Dag lieve familie.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2507256</guid>
				<title>Thanks</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2507256</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 23:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>John III</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2740151</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>I somehow came across one of your articles recently. It wasn't on a topic of any particular interest to me, but something about your analytical approach and clear thinking captivated me, so I looked around on your site for more and found your book on psychopaths.</p> <p>That became one of the most interesting and useful books I've read in years. Seems like a very reasonable model of psychopathy that aligns with my own unfortunate multiple experiences with these people. But aside from the content there is something about the way you think and write that really resonates with me. I look forward to reading your other books.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2507225</guid>
				<title>A few words from one of your readers</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2507225</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 22:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>frankrousseau</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2740146</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Hello Pieter,</p> <p>I recently read your last article. It touched me. It's something unusual for me to feel sad for someone I've never met. You helped me in several ways trough the ZMQ guide and your publications. I keep on coming back to them to find inspiration. So today, I wanted to say hi.</p> <p>First, the ZMQ guide allowed me to learn most common communication patterns used in distributed software. In my programming career (15+ years), I've always found interest in distributed systems without really thinking about their internals. Unfortunately, when I built them, I focused more on the usage than on the protocol. That's why I have mainly used only two patterns: pub/sub and request/reply. So, reading the guide was the opportunity to learn more about the subject and feel less ignorant.</p> <p>Second, I discovered the chapters about projects, community, contracts and contribution management. The tips provided and the clarity of your explanation were very helpful to bootstrap the Cozy project (a platform to make personal server management easy), to hire and make a team to work properly on it and to allow contributions from the community. Of course, I would love to have done as good as you did with ZMQ, but I'm already satisfied with the job done so far. By the way, I can't count the time I made reference to your guide during my pitches to the team.</p> <p>Last but not least, you provided me with guidance to deal with psychopaths. I met several of them in my life. The last one was my roommate. It was especially hard and reading your essays made me more confident when facing the situation. Finally, I used the technic of total submission without any reaction (to make her feel bored) while working on building a juridic case and collecting emails from her where she shows clearly no rational thinking and suspicious behavior. As soon as the first sign of external authority came to her (a letter from the moderator mandated by the town hall), she flew away.</p> <p>Why I share you all that things with you? Just to say a big thank you. You do precise work, share your knowledge and tell good stories. It's beautitful and useful at the same time. It's like mixing art and design.<br /> I wish one day, I will be able to do something similar. Whatever, I will count you as one of my biggest source of inspiration until I'll apply your protocol.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2506662</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2506662</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 20:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>pieterh</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>99</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Thank you for buying the book. It means a lot to me, that people read these.</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2506647</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2506647</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 19:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>Thomas Bollaert</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>2739053</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Hi Pieter</p> <p>I didn't know about your work until now. I came across your website after reading an article about you in the newspaper. You inspired me with your blogpost, your Lego-story which you told your children and your way of thinking in general. I envy your strength.</p> <p>I decided to buy your book &quot;Culture &amp; Empire&quot; (maybe you're smiling reading this now :) ) Not only because if I also have an interest in computer science, also cause I'm sure your book will be mighty interesting.</p> <p>I want you to fully enjoy the last moments of your life with friends and close relatives.</p> <p>Thanks</p> <p>Thomas</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
					<item>
				<guid>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2502953</guid>
				<title>(no title)</title>
				<link>http://hintjens.com/blog:115/comments/show#post-2502953</link>
				<description></description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 15:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<wikidot:authorName>alexandra bond</wikidot:authorName>				<wikidot:authorUserId>30171</wikidot:authorUserId>				<content:encoded>
					<![CDATA[
						 <p>Pieter - I can't find the words. My thoughts are with you<br /> and with your family. You will be missed. Alex</p> 
				 	]]>
				</content:encoded>							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>